{"tossups": [{"question": "A member of this party earned the nickname \u201cSockless Jerry\u201d in a election against J.R. Hallowell. This party nominated Thomas Watson for vice president in a temporary alliance with the Democrats. The NFAIU, a precursor to this political party, issued the Ocala Demands, calling for the abolition of national banks. This party outlined its beliefs in the Omaha Platform. The Farmers Alliance grew into, for ten points, what political party that rallied against railroads in the late 19th century?", "answer": "<b> People\u2019s</b> Party (or<b> Populist</b> Party)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This treaty\u2019s signing was delayed by the policy of \u201cno war and no peace\u201d in an attempt to buy time for more revolutions to occur. One side was forced to sign the unfavorable terms of this treaty after they were targeted in Operation Faustschlag. The Treaty of Rapallo annulled all territorial claims of this treaty, which included recognizing the independence of Ukraine and ceding the Baltic States to Germany. For ten points, name this harsh treaty, a separate peace that took Russia out of World War I.", "answer": "Treaty of<b> Brest-Litovsk</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The Halifax dockyards once maintained, for ten points, what force that worked with the American and British navies to protect Atlantic convoys?", "answer": "<b> Canadian Navy</b> (prompt on partial answers, like \u201cthe Navy\u201d or \u201cthe armed forces of Canada\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Photographer Cindy Sherman created a series of these works called \u201cUntitled Film Stills.\u201d A figure wearing a tunic adorned with the Cross of Santiago at the left hand side of<em> Las Meninas</em> is this type of artwork. Monkeys, necklaces of thorns, and hummingbirds appear in many of these works by Frida Kahlo, whose<em> Broken Column</em> was painted after she underwent spinal surgery. A bandaged ear is featured in one of these works by Vincent Van Gogh. For ten points, name this type of artwork that depicts its creator.", "answer": "<b> self-portrait</b>s (accept descriptions of<b> portraits</b> of the<b> artist</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "In the first crisis dissolved by this presidential doctrine, negotiator Robert Murphy led a delegation that carried out Operation Blue Bat, assisting the government of the Maronite Christian Camille Chamoun. The phrase \u201cinternational communism\u201d was central to this doctrine, which expanded the potential of intervention beyond Soviet-driven military conflicts. For ten points, name this presidential doctrine, first invoked in Lebanon in 1958, that was outlined by a former World War II general.", "answer": "<b> Eisenhower</b> Doctrine Page 2", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A raid by Robert Seales prompted this city to build the Castillo de San Marcos. In an attack on this city, Fort Mos\u00b4e was captured by forces under James Oglethorpe. After Francis Drake led a 1586 attack on this city, he sailed for Roanoke. The founder of this city massacred the nearby Fort Caroline, which had been founded by Jean Ribault and his Huguenot followers. Pedro Mend\u00b4ez de Avil\u00b4es founded, for ten points, what Florida city, the oldest continuously occupied European settlement in the United States?", "answer": "<b> Saint Augustine</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Thomas Willis and Nicolaus Steno independently published groundbreaking texts on these things in the 1660s. Camillo Golgi and Santiago Cajal [ca-HAL] revolutionized the study of these things through their use of a staining procedure. Hippocrates and Aristotle disagreed on the function of this object, the latter believing that they were for cooling blood. Thomas Harvey took this object from Albert Einstein without permission. For ten points, name this body part that is controversially operated on in a lobotomy.", "answer": "<b> brain</b>s (accept any specific region of the brain, like<b> prefrontal lobe</b> after \u201clobotomy\u201d is read)", "metadata": "Science - Biology"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s election to the Reichstag conveniently made him immune to Bernhard Weiss\u2019 [vice\u2019s] charges of libel for what this man printed in his newspaper<em> Der Angriff</em>, or<em> The Attack</em>. This man gave a speech at the Sportpalast arena in which the phrase \u201cand storm break loose\u201d was used to prepare citizens for total war. This man, who attempted to keep morale high by promising new \u201cWunderwaffen,\u201d gave his six children cyanide pills and committed suicide with his wife in the Fuhrerbunker. For ten points, name this propaganda minister of Nazi Germany.", "answer": "(Paul) Joseph<b> Goebbels</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "A ship of this name was towed out of Boston harbor by the<em> Halifax</em> after its crew locked a customs inspector in its hold to smuggle its cargo of Portuguese wine ashore. John Hancock owned that ship of this name, which was burned by defiant colonists in Newport. A group named after this concept razed Andrew Oliver\u2019s house and met at namesake \u201cpoles\u201d erected in colonial cities. A group that opposed the Stamp Act was called the \u201cSons of,\u201d For ten points, what concept that Patrick Henry demanded, \u201cor give me death\u201d?", "answer": "<b> liberty</b> (accept Sons of<b> Liberty</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Cooperation with this policy was led by Mike Masaoka with the JACL. This policy was undermined by the Ringle Report, which was purposely withheld by Charles Fahy. The Civil Liberties Act of 1988 apologized for this policy and established reparation payments. This policy was supported by Executive Order 9066, which claimed to combat espionage. The legality of this practice was upheld in<em> Korematsu v.</em> <em>United States</em>. For ten points, name this World War II policy in which a specific ethnicity of East Asians were relocated to camps.", "answer": "<b> Japanese</b>-American<b> internment</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This battle began when Thomas Foley and James Samaurez sailed the<em> Orion</em> and<em> Goliath</em> through a narrow strait between the mainland and the enemy ship<em> Guerrier</em>. In this battle, poorly stowed jars of paint may have caused an explosion aboard the<em> L\u2019Orient</em>, where Vice Admiral Brueys died after being struck by a cannonball. Napoleon\u2019s troops were unable to return to Europe after Horatio Nelson was victorious at, for ten points, what 1798 naval battle near the mouth of a namesake Egyptian river?", "answer": "Battle of the<b> Nile</b> (accept, but do<em> not</em> otherwise reveal, Battle of<b> Aboukir Bay</b>; if they give that, just give them 20 points right away)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>In 1643, this country led an abortive expedition to establish a colony at Valdivia in Chile. This country lost the Battles of Guararapes, ending its brief possession of Recife that had</b> <b>begun with a 1630 attack on Pernambuco, part of its \u201cGrand (+)</b> <b>Design\u201d strategy. This</b> <b>country suspended payments to a former colony after Desi Bouterse\u2019s regime perpetrated the December Murders. The ABC Islands and (*)</b> Suriname were once colonies of, for ten points, what European country that once controlled Aruba and Cura\u00b8cao under the nominal rule of Queen Beatrix?", "answer": "Republic of the (Seven) United<b> Netherlands</b> (accept the<b> Dutch</b> Republic)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>William Russell and a member of this family named Alphonso co-founded Yale\u2019s Skull and Bones society. Under the Insular Government, a member of this family served as</b> <b>Governor-General of the (+)</b> <b>Philippines. A member of this family restricted the power</b> <b>of unions in a bill he co-sponsored with Fred Hartley. Edward White was succeeded as (*) </b>Chief Justice by a member of this family who, 11 years earlier, had originally named White to the post. For ten points, name this political family that included Senator Robert and President William Howard.", "answer": "<b> Taft</b> family (accept Alphonso<b> Taft</b>; accept William Howard<b> Taft</b>; accept Robert<b> Taft</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>One of the main producers of these goods hired surveyor Gavino Guttierez to create a new site for his \u201cPrince of Wales\u201d brand. Production of these goods have been concentrated in locations called</b><em><b> chichales</b></em> <b>[chee-CHAL-ays]. Because of the Ten Years War, production</b> <b>of these goods was moved to (+)</b> <b>Ybor City. Workers who created these goods often paid</b> <b>part of their wages to a lector, who would read newspapers and other works to them for entertainment. An (*) </b> embargo on these items by JFK was partially lifted in 2016. For ten points, name this product that<em> tabaqueros</em> roll in Havana.", "answer": "Cuban<b> cigar</b>s (prompt on tobacco; do not accept cigarettes)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Eleazar Miller oversaw a famous one of these events near a mill. Manteo was the first Native American to undergo one version of this process. Kateri Tekakwitha underwent this</b> <b>process at the hands of the French, leading the (+)</b> <b>Mohawk to accuse her of witchcraft.</b> <b>The Nauvoo Temple contains a place where individuals can conduct this process on the (*)</b> dead, an act allowed by the Mormon church. For ten points, name this sacramental process in which Christians immerse themselves in water.", "answer": "<b> baptism</b> (accept word forms) Page 10", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man gained fame for cautiously observing rules known as</b><em><b> Dicta Boelcke</b></em><b>, in contrast to his more aggressive brother Lothar. \u201cBloody April\u201d was this man\u2019s most successful month, coming while operating an Albatros D.III [d-three]. Cedric (+) Popkin is generally accepted as firing the shot that killed this leader of</b><em><b> Jasta 11</b></em><b>, although Arthur Roy Brown, operating a (*)</b> Sopwith Camel, was initially credited. A unit nicknamed the \u201cFlying Circus\u201d was led by, for ten points, what German World War I ace?", "answer": "the<b> Red Baron</b> (or Manfred Albrecht Freiherr von<b> Richthofen</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}